<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd">
    <teiHeader xml:lang="en">
        <encodingDesc>
            <appInfo>
                <application ident="GROBID" version="0.4.1" when="2018-10-26T07:57+0000">
                    <ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
                </application>
            </appInfo>
        </encodingDesc>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="a" type="main">Synthesis and investigation of SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposites with different GO concentrations: structure and optical properties, photocatalytic performance</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher/>
                <availability status="unknown">
                    <licence/>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblStruct>
                    <analytic>
                        <author>
                            <persName>
                                <forename type="first">Atefeh</forename>
                                <surname>Rahimi</surname>
                            </persName>
                            <affiliation key="aff1">
                                <orgName key="dep1" type="department">Physics Department</orgName>
                                <orgName key="dep2" type="department">Faculty of Science</orgName>
                                <orgName type="institution">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</orgName>
                                <address>
                                    <settlement>Ahvaz</settlement>
                                    <country key="IR">Iran</country>
                                </address>
                            </affiliation>
                        </author>
                        <author role="corresp" sequence="1">
                            <persName>
                                <forename type="first">Iraj</forename>
                                <surname>Kazeminezhad</surname>
                            </persName>
                            <contact>
                                <email>I.Kazeminezhad@scu.ac.ir</email>
                            </contact>
                            <affiliation key="aff1">
                                <orgName key="dep1" type="department">Physics Department</orgName>
                                <orgName key="dep2" type="department">Faculty of Science</orgName>
                                <orgName type="institution">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</orgName>
                                <address>
                                    <settlement>Ahvaz</settlement>
                                    <country key="IR">Iran</country>
                                </address>
                            </affiliation>
                            <affiliation key="aff2">
                                <orgName type="department">Center for Research on Laser and Plasma</orgName>
                                <orgName type="institution">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</orgName>
                                <address>
                                    <settlement>Ahvaz</settlement>
                                    <country key="IR">Iran</country>
                                </address>
                            </affiliation>
                        </author>
                        <author>
                            <persName>
                                <forename type="first">Seyed</forename>
                                <forename type="middle">Ebrahim</forename>
                                <surname>Mousavi Ghahfarokhi</surname>
                            </persName>
                            <affiliation key="aff1">
                                <orgName key="dep1" type="department">Physics Department</orgName>
                                <orgName key="dep2" type="department">Faculty of Science</orgName>
                                <orgName type="institution">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</orgName>
                                <address>
                                    <settlement>Ahvaz</settlement>
                                    <country key="IR">Iran</country>
                                </address>
                            </affiliation>
                        </author>
                        <title level="a" type="main">Synthesis and investigation of SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposites with different GO concentrations: structure and optical properties, photocatalytic performance</title>
                    </analytic>
                    <monogr>
                        <imprint>
                            <date/>
                        </imprint>
                    </monogr>
                </biblStruct>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term>SnS 2 /RGO nancomposite‚ Structural properties</term>
                    <term>Optical properties‚ Photocatalytic activity</term>
                    <term>Acid orange 7 1 Introduction</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <abstract>
                <p>In this study, we report the synthesis of tin disulfide/reduced graphrene oxide (SnS 2 /RGO) nanocomposites by a simple one-step hydrothermal method. In order to investigate the effect of RGO on the structure and optical properties and photocatalytic activity of the products a series of nanocomposites was prepared with different concentrations of GO. The samples were examined using X-ray diffraction (XRD), field emission scanning electron microscopy (FESEM), Raman spectroscopy, UV-vis spectroscopy and Photoluminescence (PL) techniques. The results confirmed the growth of SnS 2 with the hexagonal phase. FESEM analysis showed that the hexagonal tin disulfide nanoplates are uniformly dispersed on the surface of the graphene oxide sheets. The optical examination of SnS 2 and SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposites indicated that the band gaps of all nanocomposites are greater than that of SnS 2 due to the quantum confinement effect. The photocatalytic activity of the SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposites was investigated for degradation of the acid orange 7 dye under visible light. It was observed that all nanocomposites have a higher photocatalytic activity for the degradation in comparison with pure SnS 2. The optimum concentration of GO in SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposite for achieving the highest photocatalytic efficiency (81%) was determined as 2mg ml-1 during 180 min. Entrance of colored wastewater in the environmental medium has created many problems for human health and that of other living beings. So far, several methods have been used to remove dye pollutants from wastewaters. One of the effective and preferable approaches for removing organic pollutants is photocatalytic degradation of dyes method [1,2]. In recent decades, titanium dioxide (TiO 2) as an environmentally friendly photocatalyst has shown good photocatalytic performance with respect to other discovered photocatalysts; however, due to its relatively wide band gap of 3.2 eV, it does not respond in the visible region which includes about 46% of the sunlight [3]. Therefore, many researchers have paid attention to the development of visible light responsive photocatalysts. Metal dichalcogenides such as MoSe 2 , MoS 2 , WSe 2 and WS 2 have been recently reported as photocatalysts in visible light [4-7]. Tin disulfide (SnS 2) is another useful metal dichalcogenide with hexagonal CdI 2 crystal structure [8]. In this structure, tin atoms are sandwiched between two close packed sheets of sulfur anions and they are bounded by week van der Waals forces [9]. SnS 2 has an enormous range of application and unique properties‚ such as being inexpensive, non-toxic, chemically stable in acid and neutral aqueous media, and thermally stable in the air. In addition, narrow band gap (2.2 eV) and sensitivity to visible light photocatalyst could be an alternative for this manner [10]. Photocatalytic application of SnS 2 is restricted significantly due to the photocorrosion problem and high recombination rate of its photoinduced charge carriers [11]. However, combination of SnS 2 with different materials such as SnO 2 ‚ TiO 2 ‚ g-C 3 N 4 ‚ Ag 2 CO 3 ‚ WO 3 , and graphene has improved its photocatalytic activity [12-17]. Recently, graphene has been found as one of the most promising semiconductors in the field of nanoscience due to its high electrical and thermal conductivities, high surface area (~ 2600 m 2 g-1) and mobility of charge carriers (230000 cm 2 v-1 s-1) [18]. It is regarded as an extremely attractive component for the preparation of semiconductor/reduced graphene nanocomposites for many applications such as solar cells, ion batteries and photocatalytic activities [19-22]. The aim of this study is to investigate the optical properties of SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposites synthesized with different concentrations of graphene oxide using UV-visible and PL spectroscopies and also to study the photocatalytic degradation of acid orange 7 (AO7) dye from polluted water by the composite. 2. Exprimental details: 2.1 Materials Graphite powder, sodium nitrate (NaNO 3 , 99%), sulfuric acid (H 2 SO 4 , 98%)‚ hydrochloric acid (HCl, 30%)‚ hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 , 30%) and thiourea (CH 4 N 2 S, 99%) were purchased from Merck (Germany). Potassium permanganate (KMnO 4 , 99%) and tin (IV) chloride pentahydrate (Korea). All materials were used as received without further purification. 2.2 Sample preparation 2.2.1 Preparation of graphite oxide Graphite oxide (GO) was synthesized from graphite powder with a modified Hummer's method [23,24]. 2 g graphite powder, 1 g sodium nitrate and 46ml sulfuric acid were mixed under magnetic stirring. Then 6 g potassium permanganate was slowly added to the mixture under ice bath conditions, and followed by stirring 2h at 35°C, 92 ml deionized water was poured into the mixture and stirred. The reaction was stopped by adding extra deionized water and hydrogen peroxide to obtain a yellow suspension. Finally, the precipitate was washed several times with HCl and deionized water and dried at 60 °C for 24 h. 2.2.2 Preparation of SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposite SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposites were prepared by a simple one-step hydrothermal method. In order to separate graphite oxide sheets from one another, a certain amount of graphite oxide powder was dispersed in deionized water using ultrasonic bath for 1 hour. Change of the solution color to brown confirmed the formation of GO. 1.92g of tin chloride pentahydrate (SnCl 4 .5H 2 O) was added to the aqueous GO and dispersed with a magnetic stirrer for 1 hour at room temperature. Then 1.28 g thiourea (CH 4 N 2 S) was added as sulfide source and after 30 min the obtained solution was transferred into the Teflon-lined autoclave‚ and heated at 180 ° C for 16 h. Finally, the container was left to cool down at room temperature naturally. Eventually, deposits were collected by centrifugation and washed with deionized water several times and dried at 80 ° C for 5 h. The samples were synthesized with three concentrations of graphene oxide such as 1, 2, and 3mg ml-1. 2.3 Characterization The prepared samples were examined by X-ray diffraction (XRD) PW-1840 Philips diffractometer with CuK α radiation wavelength of λ=1.5418 Å and their morphologies were characterized using a TESCAN field emission scanning electron microscope (FESEM) which was equipped to an energy dispersive X-ray (EDX) analyzer. The Raman spectra were recorded using Teksan spectroscopy (model: Takram P50C0R10) with 532 nm laser excitation (Nd:YAG laser) from 200 to 2000 cm-1. UV-vis absorption spectra of the samples and the treated wastewater were recorded by a Photonix Ar (P.P CO. Ltd) spectrophotometer. Photoluminescence (PL) spectra of the products were recorded by a fluorescence spectrometer (Lumina; Thermo Fisher Scientific) with a 150 W Xenon lamp at an excitation wavelength of 375nm. 2.4 Photocatalytical measurements In order to investigate the photocatalytic performance of SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposites‚ the photodegradation of acid orange 7 was examined using the composite as phortocatalyst. 0.1g of the photocatalyst was added to 100 ml of the dye solution with 20 mgl-1 concentration. To achieve the adsorption/desorption equilibrium time, the mixture was stirred and left in the dark for 180 min and the samples were taken at equal intervals in time, such as 15-minute intervals, and finally the absorptions of the samples were examined by a UV-vis spectrophotometer. The equilibrium time of each sample which represents the minimum time for having maximum absorption of acid orange 7 in the dark was determined by the UV results. In this stage of the study, the fresh polluted solution was performed and carried out in the home-made photoreactor with a 55w xenon lamp. The mixture was left in the dark and after passing the equilibrium time, it was irradiated by the lamp while it was being stirred and the sampling was performed at equal time intervals of 30 minutes. After collecting the sediment photocatalyst from the dye mixture using a 6000 rpm centrifuge‚ the probable dye concentration in the treated solution was measured from its UV-visible spectrum. The degradation efficiency is calculated by the below equation [25]: 0 0 () / 100 C C C     where C 0 and C are the dye concentrations at initial and time t‚ respectively. 3 Results and discussion: 3.1 Structure and morphology analysis Figure 1 shows XRD patterns of GO‚ SnS 2 , and SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposites with different concentrations of GO. The pattern of GO shows a relatively strong peak at 9.93 which corresponds to increasing interlayer distance from 0.33 nm (precursor graphite) to 0.89 nm indicating the existence of functional groups after oxidation of graphite [26]. All of the peaks in the XRD pattern can be readily indexed to a pure hexagonal phase of SnS 2 with a lattice constant a=3.649Å‚ c=5.899Å (JCPDS:23-0677). The patterns of SnS 2 /RGO nanocomposites are also similar to that of the SnS 2 and no sign of other phases such as S‚ SnS and SnO 2 can be observed. A lack of GO peak in the XRD</p>
            </abstract>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text xml:lang="en"/>
</TEI>